Alchemy is a science where one understands the structure of matter, breaks it down, then rebuilds it.
錬金術は物質を理解分解再構築する科学なり
However, it is not an all-powerful technique,
as one cannot create something out of nothing.
されど　万能の技にはあらず
無から有を生ずることあたわず
If one wishes to gain something,
one must present something of equal value.
何かを得ようと欲すれば
必ず同等の代価を支払うものなり
This is the concept of equivalent exchange, the fundamental basis of alchemy.
これすなわち錬金術の基本　等価交換なり
However, there is a taboo in alchemy. Human transmutation.
錬金術師に禁忌あり
そは人体錬成なり
One must not commit this act.
これ何人も犯すことなかれ
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
この想いを　消してしまうには
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
I want to go back and finish
やり残してるコト
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
やり直してみたいから
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
夢のつづき　追いかけていたはずなのに
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
曲がりくねった　細い道　人につまずく
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
あの頃みたいにって　戻りたい訳じゃないの
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
無くしてきた空を　探してる
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
わかってくれますように
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
犠牲になったような　悲しい顔はやめてよ
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
罪の最後は涙じゃないよ
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
ずっと苦しく背負ってくんだ
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
出口見えない感情迷路に
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
誰を待ってるの？
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
白いノートに綴ったように
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
もっと素直に吐き出したいよ
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
何から　逃れたいんだ
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
…現実ってやつ？
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
叶えるために　生きてるんだって
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
叫びたくなるよ　聞こえていますか？
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
無難になんて　やってられないから
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
…帰る場所も無いの
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
優しさには　いつも感謝してる
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
だから強くなりたい(I'm on the the
(I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
懐かしくなる
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
こんな痛みも歓迎じゃん
Konna itami mo kangei jan
Maes Hughes is dead.
マース·ヒューズは死んだ
He was murdered by mysterious people who have tattoos of Ouroboros.
ウロボロスの入れ墨を持つ
謎の者たちに殺されたのだ
Mustang, doubtful of the reason behind Hughes' death, upon learning the military leadership had a hand in the plot,
その死に疑問を抱いたマスタングは
軍上層部の関与を知り
decided to make his way to Central.
改めて　セントラルへの進出を決意する
一方　何も知らないエドとアルは
At the same time, Ed and Al, knowing nothing of this, headed south with Winry toward Dublith where their master lives.
ウィンリィとともに
師匠が住むダブリスの街を目指して
南部へと旅立った　だが…
However...
Rush Valley!
ラッシュバレー
Automail!
機械鎧　機械鎧
Automail~
Automail!
機械鎧
I'm so blessed!
幸せ
It's a Gotts eleventh year model!
ゴッズの１１年モデル
I never thought I'd be able to lay my eyes on one!
まさか　この目で拝める日が来るなんてぇ
As expected from the Holy Land of Automails.
さすが機械鎧の聖地
This place is packed.
すごいにぎわいだね
けっ　何が楽しくてこのクソ暑い中
Where's the fun in staring at automails all day in this hot weather?
機械鎧拝まなきゃなんねぇんだよ
ウィンリィ置いてさっさとダブリス行きゃあよかったぜ
We should have just left Winry
and headed straight for Dublith!
Hey you, do you have a moment?
君　ちょっといいかな
This automail's a rare make.
珍しい形の機械鎧だね
You're right. Take a look, everyone.
本当だ　みんなも見てみろ
Hey.
おっ ちょっと
Hey, whoa-
おっ　おっと　やめろ
Cut it out! C-Cut it-
や　やめよ
や　やめろって　そこ
I said cut it out! N-Not there!
そ　そこはダメ　ダ　ウワー
No! N-No!!!
Everyone's so eager to learn!
みんな研究熱心だわ
Get off me!
ふざけんな
Geez... This is why I can't stand automail mechanics...
ったく これだから機械鎧技師ってやつは
U-Umm...
Huh?
あれ
What's wrong?
どうしたの
I can't find it...
ない
Find what?
何が
The sign of a State Alchemist...
国家錬金術師の証し
...my silver pocket watch!
銀時計が
I can't find it.
ない
That's probably Paninya's doing.
そりゃきっとパニーニャの仕業だ
Paninya?
パニーニャ
She's a pickpocket who goes after tourists.
観光客をカモにしてるスリだよ
Any idea where she is?
そいつがどこにいるか知らないか
It's something really important!
大事な物なんだ
I don't mind telling ya...
教えてやってもいい
...But in exchange...
だがそのかわり
Let me see your automail one last...
もう一度にいちゃんの機械鎧
She's at an automail mechanic by the name of Dominique's place!
ドミニクって名の機械鎧技師のとこです
They said he lives deep in the mountains because you can find high quality ore, but...
良質な鉱石が採れるから
山奥に住んでるっていうけど
This really is the right path... right?
ほんとにこの道で合ってるんでしょうね
They didn't trick us, did they?
だまされたんじゃないの
It's your fault for saying you wanted to go to that city in the first place!
もとはといえば
お前があんな街に行きてぇなんて言うからだろうが
Getting your silver pocket watch stolen was due to your own carelessness!
銀時計盗まれたのは自分の不注意でしょう
Shut up!
うっせぇ
Hey, you two!
ちょっと二人とも
What do you want?!
なんだ
Isn't that the girl?
あの子じゃない
Found her!!!
見つけたぁ
Give it back...
返せよ
You're amazing! What the heck are you?
すごいね
にいちゃん何者
I'm... an alchemist!
錬金　術師だぁ
Wow, awesome!
すごい　すごい
Moving about so much...
ちょこまかと
Hey, you're running out of breath!
ほらほら　息が上がってるよ
I've been waiting for you.
待ってたよ
Well done!
お見事
What do you say you give it back now...
さあ　返してもらおうか
...my silver pocket watch...
銀時計
It's not really a rare sight, is it?
Considering the city you were just at.
珍しくもないでしょ　こんな街なんだし
And also...
ちなみに
A 1.5 inch culverin in my left leg.
左足には１.５インチカルバリン砲
Wait!
待て
捕まえてごらん
Catch me if you can!
Don't even try to escape!
逃げようったってそうはいかないわよ
Good work, Winry! Don't let go of her!
でかしたウィンリィ
そいつの手離すなよ
That's the plan!
ええ　離すもんですか
I won't let go of you until you let me examine your automail!
その機械鎧
もっとよく見せてくれるまで離さないだあっ
Oh my, Paninya.
あらパニーニャ
You brought friends over?
お友達
Give up already!
ほら　観念しなさい
Well, about that...
いや その
It's my first time seeing an automail like this!
初めて見るわ　こんな機械鎧
The suspension is powerful, but what's even more amazing is the overall balance!
サスペンションも高度だけど
なんといっても全体のバランス
This efficient design is a work of art!
このムダのない設計はまさに芸術よ
Umm... about my silver pocket watch...
あの　オレの銀時計
This is amazing! How did they do this?
It's no use, Brother...
ムダだよ　兄さん
You have my deepest respect for being able to make such an automail!
うわぁ　こんな機械鎧が作れるなんて尊敬します
No, I'm not the one who made it.
いや　これを作ったのはオレじゃないよ
It's mine.
オレだ
Isn't it a bit heavy?
ちょっと重くねぇか
Yeah... I agree.
ですよね
It's not good to put a strain on the recipient.
装備者に負担が掛かるのはよくねぇ
Maybe that's why this guy's so small?
だからこいつ　ちっせぇんじゃねぇのか
Don't call me small!
ちっさい言うな
はっ
Which means I'd get bigger if it's made lighter.
ってことは　もっと軽いのにすればオレの身長も伸びる
There's a possibility.
可能性はあるな
You're huge, Brother!
兄さんおっきい
You're so tall!
背ぇ高い
You guys are so puny.
お前ら　ちっせぇなぁ
うん　やっぱり決めた
I've decided.
Mister Dominique!
ドミニクさん
Hmm?
Please make me your apprentice!
私を弟子にしてください
No can do.
やなこった
You could at least give it a little more thought...
もう少し考えてくれても
Shut up. I don't take apprentices.
うるせぇ　弟子は取らねぇ
I'm begging you!
そこをなんとか　オレの身長が伸びる機械鎧を
Could you please teach her how to build an automail that would help me grow?
伝授してやってくれませんかね
Shut up, flea.
黙れ　ミジンコ
Sorry about that.
ごめんね　おやじ頑固だからさ
My old man's pretty stubborn.
Yeah...
Flea... Flea...
ミジンコ　ミジンコ
Flea...
ミジンコ
Hm?
That's... a baby, right?
あの　赤ちゃんですよね
That's right.
そうよ
Can I feel your belly?
おなか　触ってみてもいいですか
Sure, go ahead.
どうぞ
It's kind of mysterious.
なんだか不思議だな
Yeah.
It's weird to think we were in
our mom's womb like this once, too...
僕たちもこんなふうに
お母さんのおなかの中に入っていたなんて
Are you all right?!
大丈夫
Y-Yeah...
The junctions start to ache when the weather is no good.
天気が悪いと付け根が痛むなぁ
Why do you wear an automail?
どうして　機械鎧に
I lost both my parents and my legs in a train accident.
列車事故に巻き込まれて
両親が死んじゃってね
It really felt like the end of the world for me,
私は　両足をなくしたの
since I had no relatives, nor was I able to walk at all.
身寄りもないうえに　歩けなくなったら
もう気分はこの世の終わりって感じでさ
And that's when I met Mister Dominique.
そんなとき　ドミニクさんに会ったんだ
You've got a look saying,
"I'm the most miserable person in the world".
自分がこの世でいちばん不幸だって顔しやがって
Ones like you piss me off the most!
てめぇみてぇのがいちばん腹立つ
Let me go! Let me go!
放せ　放せ
Eyes of a corpse.
死人の目
I probably looked dreadful back then...
あのときの私は　きっとひどい顔してたんだろうなぁ
And so, while I had no idea what was going on, he stuck these on me.
で　結局訳分かんないまま機械鎧付けられちゃってさ
The surgery was painful, and the rehab was backbreaking; everything was horrible.
手術は痛いわ　リハビリはしんどいわで
最悪だったね
But...
でも
When I was able to stand on my feet again,
I felt like the world was mine.
また　両足で立てたときはうれしかったなぁ
I'm really thankful to Mister Dominique.
ドミニクさんには　ほんと感謝してるんだ
I plan on repaying the debt,
even if it takes my whole life to do it.
一生掛かっても　必ずお礼をするつもり
Even though I've never gotten him to accept any kind of payment...
まだ一度だって
代金を受け取ってくれたことはないけどね
So that's why you pickpocket...
それでスリを
If you're truly thankful, then stop pickpocketing!
本当に感謝してるなら　スリなんてやめなさい
Huh?
Mister Dominique gave you these legs in good faith.
この両足はドミニクさんが誠意でくれたものよ
So you have to respond to that with the same, too!
だったら　あんたも誠意で応えなきゃダメ
If you're really planning on spending your whole life trying to repay him, stand up and work hard to earn money!
一生掛けるっていうなら
スリなんかしないで　しっかりと立って働くの
その両足で
With those legs he gave you!
I'm sure that would make Mister Dominique much happier.
その方が　きっとドミニクさんも喜ぶと思うよ
I see...
そっか
You're right!
そうだよね
Yeah! I'll stop pickpocketing!
うん　スリはやめる
I'll repay him by earning money honestly!
地道に働いて返すよ
Oh, that's right...
ああ　これ返さなきゃ
I have to give this back to him.
Right!
Huh?
あっ　あれ　まずい　壊しちゃったかな
Uh-oh... Did I break it?
It won't open...
フタが開かない
Let me see.
見せて
No, he's sealed it with alchemy.
いや違う　錬金術でフタをしてあるのよ
How come?
どうして
The answer is obvious.
そんなの決まってるじゃない
Because there's something embarrassing in here he doesn't want anyone else to see!
見られたら恥ずかしいものが入ってるからよ
うっふっふっふっふっ
Got it!
開いた
Now, let's see what Ed's got in here...
さあ　エドのお宝拝見
"Don't forget. 3. Oct. 11."
「忘れるな　１１年１０月３日」
What is this?
なんだろ
Please give this back to Ed.
これ　エドに返しといて
Winry?
ウィンリィ
I'm...
もう一回
I'm going to try asking Mister Dominique for an apprenticeship again!
ドミニクさんに弟子入りお願いしてくる
What's wrong?
どうしたの
B-Being bo...
うっ うま
Bingo?
馬
Being bo... Bo...
うま うまぁ
What about bingo?
馬がどうしたのよ
B...
B-
Miss Sadila says the baby's being born!!!
産まれるって　サテラさん
この雨じゃあ　街の病院に連れてけねぇ
We can't take her to a hospital in the city in this weather.
ひとっ走り行って　医者を呼んでくる
I'll rush over there and bring back a doctor.
おやじが　すぐ医者を連れてくるから
My old man will be back with a doctor soon.
もう少し我慢しろ　なっ
Just hang in there, okay?
我慢ったって　産まれるときは産まれる うっ
I can't exactly "hang in there"
if the baby's trying to come out...
どうした
What's wrong?!
What's she saying? I can't make it out.
なんだって　聞こえない
産まれるぅ
The baby's being born!
うっ　産まれる
B... B... Being born?!
どうすんだよ　医者もいねぇのに
What are we going to do?! There's no doctor around!
どうすんだ どうすんだ
What are we going to do?! What are we going to do?!
どうすんだ てめぇ
Hey, you! What are we going to do?!
やるしかないわ
We have to do it!
Do what?
何を
お産
The delivery.
ええっ
What?!
しゅ　出産に立ち会った経験は
D-Do you have experience delivering a baby?
ありません
I don't. But...
でも　迷ってる暇もありません
We don't have time to sit around, either!
みんなで協力して
We need to work together to help the baby be born!
赤ちゃんを取り上げます
エドとアルはお湯を沸かして
Ed and Al, you two go boil some water!
分かった
Got it!
パニーニャはタオルをあるだけ集めて
Paninya, collect all the towels you can find!
Roger!
了解
あとリドルさん
And Mr. Riddle, do you have any rubbing alcohol?
消毒用アルコールありますか
倉庫にあったと思う
I think we have some in the storehouse!
それと　サテラさんの枕もとに飲み水を
Oh, and please prepare some water for Miss Sadila to drink!
Say... Do you think she can handle this?
ねえ　彼女　大丈夫
あいつん家医者の家系で
She was born into a family of doctors,
家にあった医学関連書を
so she basically grew up reading medical books.
絵本代わりに読んで 育ったんだ
Yup.
えっ　それってちゃんと学んだわけじゃないんじゃ
What?! Then that means she didn't actually study how to...
I'm sure she only remembers those things vaguely.
うろ覚え程度の知識だとは思うけど
そんな
No way...
But right now,
だけど
今はあいつの知識と度胸に任せるしかないんだ
we need to put faith in her knowledge and courage.
お湯沸かして　消毒して
First, boil water, then sterilization...
What else is there to do?
あとなんだっけ
思い出せ　思い出せ
Try to remember... Try to remember...
ウィンリィ
Winry.
頑張れ
You can do it!
うん
Yeah.
パニーニャ　中で手伝って
Paninya, help me out in here.
O-Okay.
うっ　うん
兄さん
Brother...
肝心な時　オレは無力だ
I'm always powerless in critical moments...
痛い痛い痛い痛い
Oww! Oww! Oww! Oww!!!
死んじゃう
I'm going to die!
痛ぁい
It hurts so much!
もうダメ
I can't take it anymore!!!
神様なんていねぇと思ってるけど
I don't believe in God, but...
うん
Yeah.
今だけは　頼む
If you exist, then please... just for now...
Brother!
兄さん
H-Hey!
血　血が
B-Blood...
I can't... take it...
もうダメ
どうしたんだよ　おい
What happened? Hey!
う　産まれた
She did it!
Hooray!
やったっ
すげぇ　ほんとに産まれたよ
That's awesome! The baby was really born!
すげぇ　すげぇすげぇ
That's so awesome! Awesome, I tell you!
すげぇすげぇって　そんな子供みたいな感想を
You sound like a little kid saying that.
だっておめぇ　生命の誕生だぞ
Think about it! It's the birth of a life!
It's what alchemists have been spending hundreds of years trying to do.
錬金術師が何百年掛けて　いまだ成し得てない
A human creating a human.
人間が人間をつくるっていうことを
生命の神秘を錬金術と一緒にしないでよ
Don't group alchemy with the mysteries of life.
しょうがねぇだろ　職業柄
I can't help it; I'm an alchemist.
でも
But still, that's awesome.
やっぱりすげぇ
人間ってすげぇよ
Humans are awesome.
さて　子供は無事産まれたし
Well, since the baby was safely born,
あと　オレにできることあるか
is there anything I can help out with?
そうね　とりあえず
Good question.
For starters, help me up...
起こして
Huh?
自分よりちっさい男におんぶなんて　屈辱だわ
It's humiliating to be carried by a guy shorter than me.
落とすぞてめぇ
Don't make me drop you.
エド
Ed...
Hm?
銀時計の中身　見ちゃった
I saw what you wrote inside your silver pocket watch...
痛ぁ
Oww...
無理やり開けたのか
Did you force it open?
ごめんなさい
Sorry...
ばかやろう
Idiot.
アルにも見せたことねぇんだぞ
I haven't even shown it to Al.
どうして
But why?
自分への戒めと覚悟
A lesson for myself and to show my determination.
我ながら女々しいよ
It's kind of girly of me.
あの日のことを
That I have to hold on to that day in a shape like this...
そうやって形にして持ってなきゃいけないなんて
なんでお前が　泣くんだよ
Why are you  crying?
もう　後戻りはできねぇな
There's no going back now...
Yeah.
なんでお前が泣くんだよ
Why are you  crying?
あんたたち兄弟が泣かないから
I'm crying for  you, since neither you nor Al ever cry.
代わりに泣くの
ばかやろう
Idiot.
お前　やっぱり田舎に戻れ
Hey... I think you should go back to Resembool.
ばっちゃん一人じゃさみしいだろうしさ
Granny's probably lonely being all by herself.
ううん　帰らない
No, I'm not going back.
Hey...
エドの覚悟見たから
After seeing your determination...
私だって　半端な覚悟じゃいられない
I can't be walking around with
half-assed determination, either.
別に　お前まで一緒に
No, it's not like you have to carry the burden either...
私　もっと腕を磨いて
I want to keep getting better,
so I can equip you with better automail.
少しでもいい機械鎧を付けてあげたいの
エドが安心して旅を続けられるように
So you can continue your journey with peace of mind.
だからもう一度　ドミニクさんに弟子入りを頼んでみる
So I'm going to try asking Mister Dominique for an apprenticeship again!
そっか　頑張れ
I see...
Good luck.
Thanks.
ウィンリィ
Winry, Mister Riddle wants to see you.
リドルさんがちょっと来てほしいって
Huh? What's the matter?
あれ　どうしたの
ううん　なんでもない
No, it's nothing. I'll be right there.
すぐ行く
Paninya...
パニーニャ
痛ぁ　何すんのよ
Oww! What was that for?!
Shut up! Give me my watch back, you thief!
うるせぇ
さっさと時計返せこの盗人
右手で殴ることないじゃない
You didn't have to hit me with your right hand!
だったら左手でもう一発だ
Then I'll hit you again with my left!
おじいちゃんですよ
It's your grandpa!
かわいいなぁ
So cute!
キャラ　違う
His personality's changed...
母子共に体調良好
Both you and your baby are in excellent condition.
産後の処置も適切だね
The post-birth care was also very well done.
お産の立ち会いなんて　大人でもビビっちゃうのに
Even an adult would panic if they happened to witness childbirth for the first time.
Oh! Well... I panicked a little.
ああいいえ　もう必死でしたから
みんなには本当に世話になった
I owe all of you a huge thank you.
Especially you, young lady.
特に　嬢ちゃんには
ありがとう
Thank you so much.
そんなにかしこまらないでください
Please don't be so formal!
Oh, geez... I'm embarrassed.
まいったな　てれちゃう
どうです　ここは一つ弟子など
How about it? Taking an apprentice here might be a...
This and that are two different things.
それとこれとは話が別だ
オレは弟子は取らん
I won't take any apprentices.
が　どうしてもというんなら
But, if you insist...
ふもとに住んでる腕のいい技師を紹介してやる
I'll introduce you to a skilled technician that lives at the foot of the mountain.
U-Umm...
あ　あの
たまにお仕事を見学に来てもいいですか
Can I visit to observe your work from time to time?
孫の顔を見に　たまになら来るがいいさ
You can come visit to see my grandchild, sure.
You, too, Paninya!
そっちの跳ねっ返りもな
やばい　急げ
Oh no! Hurry!
If we miss it, we're going to have to wait
another three days for the next train to Dublith!
これ逃したら　次のダブリス行きは３日後だ
気をつけてね
Take care of yourselves, now!
You, too!
お前もな
ばっちゃんにちゃんと電話しろよ
Be sure you give Granny a call!
I don't want to hear that from you !
あんたに言われたくないわよ
Make sure you steal that geezer's techniques,
あのじじいからしっかり技術盗んで
so you can equip me with a
better automail the next time you see me!
次会うときはもっといいやつ付けてくれよな
行っちゃった
And there he goes.
You can count on me.
任せといて
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
ねえ　君は覚えていますか
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
約束　契り　初夏の風が包む
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
二人　寄り添った
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
無理な笑顔の裏
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
伸びた影をかくまう
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
だから　気づかぬふり　再生を選ぶ
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
テーブルの上の　震えない知らせ　待ち続けて
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
空白の夜も　来るはずのない朝も
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
全部わかってたんだ
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
ねえ　 いつか思い出すでしょう
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
果たせなかった　約束を抱いて
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
二人　歩き出す
Futari arukidasu
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
師匠の住む街ダブリスで
The boys reminisce of the times they were in training...
少年たちは修業時代を思い出す
...when they visit Dublith, the city where their master lives.
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
それは真理への第一歩
That becomes their first step toward the truth.
次回　鋼の錬金術師　FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
第十二話　一は全　全は一
Episode 12, One is All, All is One.
言葉を躊躇する　それは自らを守りたいから
He hesitates to speak,
because he wants to protect them.